Welcome back. In this lesson,
you're going to learn the basics of a very colorful part of the web.
It's called CSS or Cascading Style Sheets.
It's how webpages get all their decoration, all the colors,
fonts and layout that you see on the web are provided by CSS.
Using CSS, you'll be able to greatly improve the look of your HTML pages.
That can be anything from changing the color of
your text to completely changing the layout.
While you're learning about jazzing up your webpage,
you'll also be stretching your knowledge of computer language syntax.
You'll get a better understanding of how computer languages are put
together and that will serve you well throughout your introduction to programming.