CSS also lets you combine selectors.
For instance, you might want to say ''Make emphasized text red,
but only if it's part of a list item.''
Here's how you would do that,
in the selector part of the rule,
you write the selector for the parent element Li,
and then for the child element em.
Together, this selector means 'Select every em element that's a child of an Li element.
With that style applied,
this html will look like this.
The em element in the list item,
turns red, but the other em doesn't,
because it's not part of an Li.
This kind of selector that uses a space to create a combined selector,
Li space em, is called the descendant selector.
There are actually a whole bunch of other kinds of selectors in CSS.
I'm going to suggest you take a look at
the Mozilla CSS documentation for selectors if you'd like to see more of them though.