Okay. So, you've seen a bunch of things that you can do with CSS,
but here's a question we haven't answered yet,
what's so cascading about cascading style sheets?
Well, cascading has to do with how each node in the dom tree gets its styles defined.
Basically, any style property defined on a node will
apply as a default to all that nodes descendants.
Let's say that we have a document whose body looks like this,
and we have CSS rules like this.
What we want to know is what color will each
of these text nodes become when it's displayed in the browser.
To find out, we'll walk through the dom tree visiting each node starting at the top.
If there's a CSS rule for that node,
we'll apply that style to it,
but each node will also inherit style from its parent node.
We start with the body node.
There's a rule for that.
This rule says to make this white text on a black background.
Then we'll go down the left branch to h1,
we don't have a rule for h1 so it gets the same style as its parent.
Then we go to the text node "All about."
That gets the same style as its parent the h1.
Over to the em node here,
we have two different rules that might give this node its color.
We've got a rule for EM and another rule for h1 em.
In this case, the most specific selector applies.
Here, that's the h1 em rule.
So this gets to be orange not red,
but the h1 em rule doesn't define the background color,
so, that'll be inherited from above.
This text node that says CSS,
that'll also inherit the orange on black style from its parent.
Over to the right side of the tree,
the p node matches the CSS rule for p,
so, it gets pink,
p for pink paragraph.
Still inheriting the black background from the body though,
and those will cascade down to this text node but over here,
we've got an em node that will be painted red,
and that'll cascade down to the text node below. Awesome.
So, that's what so cascading about cascading style sheets.
Each style property that's defined on a node will cascade
or spill down the tree to that node's children and descendants.
The black background color in this example cascaded to every node on the tree,
but each of these text colors only cascaded within a particular sub-tree.