One of the things we can use CSS for is to change the layout of elements on the page.
This means, we can move them around, change their sizes,
reshape them, and change the way they get positioned around each other.
In order to talk about where those elements are on the page,
we need to have units of measurement.
Just as in everyday life,
we might use meters or feet,
or miles or kilometers to say where something is or how big it is,
in CSS, we have some various units that we use.
The basic unit of measurement in CSS is the pixel,
or px for short.
Pixels are the unit that you'll see developer tools
using to measure the size of a box element.
Now, normally, a pixel is a single dot of color on your screen.
But computer screens don't all have the same size pixels.
In particular, the actual hardware pixels on
new mobile devices are really tiny compared to the pixels on older computer screens.
In CSS, the unit called pixel or px Isn't really a hardware pixel.
Instead, it's defined as being one-ninety sixth of an inch.
Ninety-six pixels per inch was
a common screen resolution when CSS was being standardized.
So, that's what the CSS px unit was set to.
Yeah, sorry metric fans,
CSS measurement is defined in terms of traditional American units,
there are 96 CSS pixels to the inch,
which means there are 37.8 CSS pixels to the centimeter.
Here's an example of how we can use these units.
Let's say that we have a p element with class skinny,
and we want to make it appear two inches wide on the screen.
The CSS property width sets how wide and element will appear.
To select the element,
we'll use the class selector.skinny,
and then we'll add a declaration width: 192 px;,
and when that's applied to this html,
we get a skinny paragraph, two inches wide.
Remember, the class name skinny is just something we
made up in order to attach this rule set to that paragraph.
We could have named it Aardvark instead,
but that wouldn't be very descriptive.
There are other units in CSS too.
One traditional typographic unit is the point, or pt.
You've probably seen this on word processors like MS Word,
or Google Docs, where you can have a 12 point font,
or a 36 point font, or the like.
A point is just one-seventy second of an inch.
In CSS, points aren't only for font size,
but that's where they're most common.
Some units were pretty differently though.
Whereas px and points are based on inches,
which is a real-world measure of length,
other CSS units are relative to the size of something else on the page.
One of these is the em,
and em is equal to the font size of the text in the element.
So, if you're using an 18 point font,
then 1em is 18 points