So, you've seen before that when the browser renders html,
every element has an invisible box around it, well usually invisible.
These are the boxes that you've seen when you're looking around pages in developer tools.
There are a whole bunch of things that we can set about any of these boxes using CSS.
There's the width, the height of the box, there's the padding,
which is the space around the contents of the box,
outside the padding is the box's border,
which is usually invisible,
but you can turn it on with CSS.
Then, there's the margin,
which is a space that the browser makes between this box, and other boxes.
Each of these is something that you can set a value measured
in CSS units such as pixels or m's.
Let's take a look at this with a couple of fancy little boxes and a big ole webpage.
Let's try configuring some of these properties for these boxes.
We'll start out by setting a border, border five pixels.
To make the border visible,
we'll also say we'll make it solid green.
That's something that you can do with borders, and hey,
now our boxes have green borders around them,
but right now these boxes are jammed up into each other,
and that's kind of ugly.
How far apart should we space them?
Well, how about one M that's the same as the height of this text the inside them.
So, let's do that, margin: 1em.
The thing is the text inside these boxes is crowded up against those borders,
we can fix that by adding padding.
Let's make the padding a little bit smaller than the margin,
maybe half an m, padding: 0.5em.
There we go, now the text is a little bit more comfortable in the boxes.
Notice that the padding is space inside the boxes borders,
whereas the margin is space outside the border.
Finally, right now these boxes are the full width of the page,
that's how block elements usually start out by default.
Let's make them a little bit smaller than that.
Let's say width: 100px, and height: 50px.
Ah, there we go.
That's looking more like something that we could use on a web page.
Okay. One more thing,
let's get these boxes to move out of the way.
We can do this by telling CSS to make them float right,
which makes the browser tries to set them at the right side of the page.
Float is one of the many ways that we can change the positioning of the box using CSS.
You'll learn a couple more ways later in the lesson.