Pretty often in CSS,
we don't want to say make this box exactly 200 pixels wide.
We want to say something more like,
make this box take up half of the page width,
but we don't know how wide the user's browser window is.
So, we can't just say a number of pixels,
or EMs, or something for this.
What we can do is use a percentage.
When we set the width or the height of a box to be a percentage like 50 percent,
we're asking the browser to make it that fraction of
the width or height of the box that it's inside.
For boxes at the top level of our document,
that makes it 50 percent of the width the whole page.
For a box that's inside another box,
it's 50 percent of the width of its parent box.
But here's something to watch out for.
By default, width doesn't include the border and it never includes the padding.
So, if you have two boxes that you want to fit next to each other using float: left,
you will usually need to make them smaller than 50 percent of the containing box.
CSS also uses percentages for something pretty different,
scaling things up or down.
For instance, let's say that we want to make strong text even stronger than usual.
We can do that by defining a style on the strong element to make the font-size,
say, 120 percent, and maybe we'll make the color red.
That means that no matter what the actual font-size in points is of the text,
any text that's in a strong element will be expanded to
120 percent of the strong node's parent font-size.