There are a lot of things you can do with CSS.
So much so, that probably one of the most important things we can teach you about CSS,
is how to find out more about what it can do.
So that's what we're going to do in this next exercise.
We'll give you a link to some reference material about CSS,
and you'll look up some properties in it.
This way you'll get used to using some of
the reference material that serious web developers use all day,
and we don't have to make ten zillion videos for all of the different features.
It's okay if the reference material looks a little overwhelming or a lot overwhelming;
this is like looking up a word in the dictionary.
When you're not quite sure how the word is spelled,
it may take you several tries searching through
it or you may end up using your favorite search engine.
That's a totally valid way of learning more too.