There are a few different ways that we can tell
the browser to apply CSS styles to our HTML.
One of them you've seen already.
We can just take the CSS code and put it into
the HTML documents head in the style element.
But this can turn out to be messy.
It's really common for a website to have many,
many HTML documents, and to want to apply the same styles to all of them.
Copying the same CSS code to each of those pages would be a big waste of space.
If we wanted to make a change to it,
we'd have to change all of those files.
So, there's another way we can do it.
We can put the CSS into a separate file,
and link to that file from the HTML.
The way we do this is to put a special tag into the HTML head link rel equals stylesheet,
href equals, and then the URL or the file name of the CSS file.
Remember the rules for relative URLs?
If we're using a CSS file that's somewhere else on the web,
we'll put a full URL in here.
But if the CSS file is in the same directory as our HTML,
and it's called say,
style.css, then we can just put that file name here.
This link element goes inside the head element of the HTML file.
We can put it right after the title element for instance.
When the browser loads this HTML file,
it will automatically load up
styles.css and apply those styles to the elements in this file.