The default way that the browser lays out the boxes onto
the page was designed for web pages that work like traditional documents.
They're made of things like headlines, paragraphs, and lists.
Pretty much in order from the top to the bottom.
This works great for pages such as wikipedia articles,
scientific papers or stories.
But, a website today can be a lot more than a document.
It's a photo gallery,
or messaging service, or a game.
So, the kind of layout that makes sense for
a document doesn't always make sense for websites today.
Apps need a much more flexible sort of layout than an article or a novel does.
CSS has grown to support that change over time.
One of the biggest improvements in
the last few years is a feature called the Flexible Box Layout,
or Flexbox for short.
It's a way to ask CSS to change the rules for how boxes are laid out onto
the page in a way that's more flexible than the usual document-based approach.
Let's take a look at what that means.
Here, I'm going to create some boxes with
different background colors so we can see how the layout changes.
Let's make all of them 100 by 100 pixels.
We'll put them inside another element that will act as a container for them.
Then put this into the browser.
Since we're using default document-oriented block layout,
these end up one after the other vertically just like paragraphs in a story.
Now, let's see what happens when I set display,
colon, flex on the container.
Wow. Now, they're side by side.
Okay, so I could do that with float, colon,
left too, but look at what happens if the browser window is resized.
These elements resize to fit the screen.
That's pretty handy, especially,
when you consider someone might be looking at
this on a phone with a really narrow window.
But Flexbox gets us something that floats don't.
We can also configure how we want the box to behave when there's not enough room on
the screen by setting the flex wrap property to the value wrap.
I can make these boxes wrapped down to the next line on a narrow browser Window.