There's something special built right into your web browser that will be
an incredibly huge help for learning more about HTML and CSS.
It's called the "Developer tools," and it's
something that every web developer spends a lot of time with.
When you get started with it,
it can seem a little overwhelming but it's also really valuable.
Every browser has a developer tools window built in,
but it'll look a bit different from one browser to another.
I'm demonstrating this using Google Chrome,
but you can use whatever browser you're already using.
They have pretty similar abilities,
although some of their names for things might be a little bit different.
Here, I've got the webpage for the World Wide Web Consortium,
and if I right-click or control-click on this page there's this option inspect,
this is one way to get at the developer tools.
Well, what are we inspecting?
This lets me look at the HTML elements for everything on this page,
starting out with what I clicked on.
So, like I said, there's a lot going on here.
Each of these tabs lets you peek into a different aspect of what the browser is doing.
For now, we'll stick to this elements tab which shows you some HTML elements.
This looks a lot like the HTML source code for this page.
As I mouse over these HTML elements,
it highlights the parts of the page that correspond to them.
This element's view and the rendered page over
on the left are two different views of the same underlying data.
But since we're doing CSS,
it's this part down here which is actually really interesting.
If I click on one of these elements down,
here I can see a bunch of information about the style of that element. Check it out.
It tells you about the background,
and the border, and the padding,
and the font, and color,
a whole bunch of things that have to do with a style and appearance of the page.
There's a pretty useful trick with this style pane over here.
Each of these pieces of style information has a little checkbox next to it.
Clicking them can turn that style on or off and that means that we can use this as
a tool to find out what the style settings
do by looking at the effects on the rendered page,
like check it out.
Turning this padding setting on or off changes the padding on the page.
This is something we should do a lot when we have a new tool.
Find out how we can use it to investigate
the world and see what we can discover about what we can change with it.