You've learned a lot of CSS techniques so far in this lesson.
Now, it's time to put a bunch of them together at once.
In the next exercise,
you'll be doing something that web developers do pretty often.
Making a web page match a design,
by adding CSS to it.
The design you'll be working with looks like this.
It's a tic-tac-toe board.
All of these x's and o's are just ordinary text.
But they're in a big size,
and a particular font.
They're on a background,
and they neatly space in their own little squares.
You'll start out with a piece of plain HTML,
and an empty CSS file.
Your job will be to fill in that CSS file.
Here's how I suggest you do it.
One step at a time.
Here's another suggestion.
Start by getting the boxes laid out in the way that you want them.
Then, work on the fonts and colors after that.
If you're completely lost,
that's okay too. Give it a try.
See what sorts of things you can do by using just CSS,
to make this layout.
On the next page, will each show you how we approach this problem.