So, here's the approach that I took to make this HTML look like the design.
The first thing I did was actually to turn a border on around each list item.
Even though we don't need that border in the final version,
it helps me see how they're being laid out.
Then, I set a width and a height on both the big box and the little boxes inside it.
The container gets to be 300 pixels high and wide,
and each item inside gets to be 90 pixels high and wide.
Now, it just looks like a big long column of boxes.
So, now I'll turn flex on and oh great,
now it's a big long row of boxes.
But if I turn on flex-wrap: wrap.
Then, hey wow, now we're making progress.
This looks really close to the layout we want except the text is all too small,
but we can fix that.
I'll set the font pretty big 80 pixels.
The design used a sans-serif font instead of this default serif font.
So, I'll add that next and there's this nice light blue background color.
Let's put that on too.
Now, we're really close.
In the design, there's a margin between the boxes,
so I'll set margin: 5px and that doesn't look right.
Oh, they're too wide because of that border I put on them.
I'll take that off now.
Now, we've got to get these dots off.
They're here because the original HTML started out with these as list items.
This is something that I had to look up,
but hey right there in the search results list-style: none.
Let me try that and hey that worked.
Now, there's just one thing wrong,
which is that all of these x's and o's are off center,
we want them to be centered.
Something else to look up search engine center text CSS and here
I found the answer in the CSS documentation in MDM text-align: center,
and with that we've matched the original design. Awesome.