All right. My approach is pretty similar to Carl's but I did a few things differently.
I'll walk you through my steps.
To start, I set the sizes of my elements so I'd have something tangible to work with.
I opened up the image and an application on my computer to see how wide the original
was and then I made a best guess on how I wanted to size my boxes.
Three boxes across 300 pixels.
So let's say, 100 pixels for each box.
I also want to have a bit of space in between,
so I'll add a margin of five pixels.
With my long column,
I needed to get my list items to go three by three in a grid.
In comes float.
Float allows items with a set width to float up into the next available space on a page.
With my big box set to 300 pixels,
I can float up to 300 pixels worth of items into the first row.
Only two list items are available to span across each row.
Let's look at that math again.
It must be because of my additional margins.
Well, let's resize the small boxes to accommodate
the margins to fit inside the big box width. That's better.
But it looks like the boxes are in the wrong order.
Using float right, it looks like the boxes
filled the rightmost space until the width is full.
Instead, I want to fill the leftmost space to keep the ordering consistent.
Let's change that here.
All right, now we're getting somewhere.
The rest of the corrections are the same as Carl's solution.
We need to get rid of the list dots,
increase the font size,
center the text, and set the font family to remove serifs.
In addition, I want to set the background color
of each of the boxes to match the sample image.
It looks like light blue,
so I'll set it to that color.
Sweet. So, that's another approach to
creating a website rendition of the tic-tac-toe design.