Wow. You've learned a lot in this lesson,
and some of the things that you've learned have been pretty advanced.
Tree structures are actually not something that
computer science students learn about until several months into a typical CS curriculum.
By learning CSS and HTML,
you've also mastered two computer languages that have very different syntax.
The grammar of HTML is built around elements made with tags.
The grammar of CSS is based on rule sets written with selectors and declarations.
Visually, CSS code and HTML code look really different,
but they do work closely together.
You've also seen that it's possible to do the same thing in
different ways such as by using a style tag or a linked style sheet file.
This is something that will keep coming up as you learn more.
In computing, there are often lots of ways to do something.
Depending on the requirements of a project,
you may find yourself doing one or the other of these things.
Up ahead, you'll be putting together a project that includes
both HTML and CSS and can also include other resources like images.
When you submit that project,
make sure to put all of the files that your project needs into a folder.
Zip up that folder and then submit the zip file.
This is your chance to be big and bold with your work.
It's important to meet the general project requirements,
but we also want you to have fun with this project.
Be inspired by your favorite websites,
but of course make sure all the work you submit is your own.
Now this project will be a bit more involved as you will be evaluated based on a rubric.
Make sure to check your work to see if it meets
all the project requirements before you submit your project.
Our expert reviewers will happily give you
feedback on your work and will either mark your project
as requires changes or meets specifications. Good luck.