One way that we can apply style to
a webpage is to visit each node of the tree and add the style we want.
There's a style attribute that we can put on html opening tags to do just that.
For instance, if we'd like to turn all of these list items green, we could do that.
We can add the style attribute,
style equals color, colon,
green, to each of the li elements.
The problem with doing it this way is that it's incredibly repetitious.
Also, if we mess up in one place,
it'll be hard to catch.
Generally in computing, if it's possible to avoid repeating yourself it's nice to do so,
not only does it save on typing but it also makes for fewer places things can go wrong.
So, what CSS lets us do is to pull all of the style information out,
and say we want to apply this style to
every li in the document instead of just one at a time.
One way we can do that is by putting a CSS rule set into
the document's head element by creating a special element called style.
The style information that we put here will be applied throughout the document.
As the browser builds up the picture on screen from the dom tree,
it'll use these style rules to color,
shape, and layout the page.