So, a CSS selector tells the browser which elements the rule will affect.
There are a few different kinds of selectors that you can use.
Actually, there are a whole lot of them,
but we're just going to look at a few of them for now.
The simplest one is a type selector,
it's just the name of one type of HTML element such as p or em.
It can even be body,
which would make the rule apply to the whole body of the HTML document.
For an example, here's a rule-set that will change the font for the entire document.
Type selectors are particularly useful when you want to
apply a style really widely across the web page.
For instance, if you're writing an article that uses a lot of section headings
with the headline elements h1 h2 and so on,
a single CSS selector will apply to all of the elements of a particular type,
but you still have to write one CSS rule for each headline element type.
This one targets every h1 element on the page and applies these styles.
This one targets every h2 element and applies these styles and so on.