Let's talk about whitespace for a moment.
You may have noticed that when you enter text in the editor,
you can put in multiple lines,
or spaces, or paragraph breaks.
But when you render it in the browser,
it's all run together.
This is because when the browser renders HTML,
all whitespace gets collapsed into a single space.
Now whitespace is a word that programmers use to talk about spaces,
tabs and line breaks.
The browser by default runs all the whitespace together,
so we don't see the line breaks that we put in.
I want this poem to show up with separate lines.
Now there's a way I can do that in HTML.
Which is to put a particular tag on each line, called BR.
BR stands for break.
As in line break.
Start a new line.
When we reload the browser window,
there, the poem shows up correctly.
Now, you might notice that there's no closing tag for the BR element.
That's because it doesn't have any contents.
There's nothing inside a line break.
It's just saying, break the line here.
We'll see a few more HTML elements like this later on.
One's that don't have a closing tag at all,
because they don't have any contents.
Elements like this are called void elements, or empty elements.
One other example of these is the IMG tag for images.
We'll see that later for now,
let's stick with text.