Next up, we're going to talk about an important concept called Nesting.
By Nesting, I just mean the idea that something can go
inside or be nested inside something else.
Here's a hands-on example.
Have you ever seen one of these Russian Matryoshka dolls,
you can open up the first one,
and there's another one inside.
And inside there, there's another one.
If you open them up, and look at them from the top,
you can see how they all fit together.
And to neatly close them up,
you have to put them back in the right order.
Anyway, HTML elements are like that.
Elements on an HTML page can go inside other elements,
but they have to follow some certain rules when they do.
For example, you can have a paragraph element that has em or mark elements inside it.
In fact, that's how HTML documents normally work.
The top level elements in the document are
things like paragraphs and other big divisions,
and inside those, are smaller elements like,
"Emphasize this text," Or "Highlight that text."
Any of these smaller elements,
can be put inside another one too.
For instance, you can have text that's both emphasized and highlighted,
or you can have things like superscripts show up inside of a piece of emphasized text.
But there are some combinations that don't work,
you can't put a paragraph inside another paragraph for instance,
and two different HTML elements,
can't overlap in the text.
One has to be entirely inside the other.
Either the sup needs to be inside the em,
or the em inside the sup.
These rules are mostly common sense,
but we'll point them out when there are unusually specific requirements.
Either element can be the little doll,
that goes inside the bigger one,
but you have to decide which one will go inside, they can't overlap.