The web is built on the idea of hypertext.
Hypertext means that you can have textual documents,
like web pages, but that they also have references between them.
On the web, those are links.
Every time you click on a link in a web page,
you're making use of hypertext.
When you write HTML,
you can link to other web pages,
both your own and also someone else's.
That's how a search engine works, for example.
So, here's how to make a link in your own HTML.
The element for making links is called .
Yes, it's not called link, it's called .
That stands for anchor,
because an  element anchors an address to a piece of text on the page.
Yeah, that sounds weird to me too,
but that's how it is, at least it's short.
But we can't just use  by itself.
There are a couple things we need an  element to include in order to make a link.
The text that a user clicks on to follow the link,
and the URL of the page we're linking to.
Here's how we're going to do that.
The opening tag for the  element has
this extra little bit in it that we haven't seen in HTML tags before.
This href equals "a url" part.
This is an example of an HTML attribute.
It's an extra piece of data that comes along
with the element and it gives it extra meaning.
The part before the equal sign is the name of the attribute,
and the part after,
in double quotes, is the value of the attribute.
Here, the name is href and the value is http://example.net.
The name href stands for hypertext reference,
and it's used with  tags and a few other tags that link to another document.
You won't ever see it on a paragraph or an emphasis tag or something else.
Then, there's the contents of the  element,
which becomes the text that appears on the page.
Then there's the closing  tag.
You might notice that it doesn't have any attributes in it.
Attributes like href always only go in the opening tag at the beginning of an element.
That's pretty much all there is to making links in HTML.
You've just made an  element with a start and an end tag.
The start tag has an href attribute with an equal sign,
and in double-quotes, the url of the page that we want to link to.
The contents of the element become the text the user clicks on,
and then there's a closing  tag.