A full HTML document actually has two parts.
Everything you've seen so far in this lesson except the Doctype Tag,
actually lives in the second of these parts,
the body of the document,
that's where the contents of the document go,
the paragraphs, images, lists,
links and other things that will appear on the screen for the user.
The other part of an HTML document is called the head and it's
where we put certain pieces of important information about the document.
Both the head and the body occur inside a single enclosing element called HTML.
Here's just a few of the things that can appear in the head of an HTML file.
The title is the only required part of the head.
It tells the browser what titled to put on a tab that's displaying the document.
We put the title in a title element with an open and a close tag.
Another thing that shows up in the head is style sheet information.
You'll learn a lot more about this later on.
Style sheets tell the browser things like what fonts and colors to use on the page,
and how to position the text.
The head can also contain scripts which are programs that run in the browser.
This is how front-end web apps work,
like the quizzes you've seen in this course for instance.
The head can also include metadata which is other information
about the page itself such as keywords for search engines.
There's also information that can go on the HTML tag itself, for instance,
this is where you can say what language your document is written in,
not the computer language, that's HTML,
but the human language such as English or French or Tibetan or Swahili.
This is helpful for programs that try to understand or pronounce
the contents of that document such as screen readers for visually impaired users.
Should the word CHAT be pronounced as 'chat' in English or as 'sha' in French?
For now, the only element of the head that you need to use is
the title tag because it's required in HTML documents.
The others you will use later as you learn more about the web.